<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-08-03T00:22:54.571Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-08-03T00:22:54.571Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public-private partnerships in health: The journey ahead for open source]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/public-private-partnerships-in-health-the-journey-ahead-for-open-source/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/public-private-partnerships-in-health-the-journey-ahead-for-open-source/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-02T23:53:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past three years have redefined the practice and management of public health on a global scale. What will we need in order to support innovation over the next three years?
The post Public-private partnerships in health: The journey ahead for open source appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Linux Foundation</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s new for NFS in Unbreakable Enterprise Kernel Release 7?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/whats-new-for-nfs-in-unbreakable-enterprise-kernel-release-7/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/whats-new-for-nfs-in-unbreakable-enterprise-kernel-release-7/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-02T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article illustrates some of the hig Click to Read More at Oracle Linux Kernel Development
The post What’s new for NFS in Unbreakable Enterprise Kernel Release 7? appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Calum Mackay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to limit container privilege with socket activation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/how-to-limit-container-privilege-with-socket-activation/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/how-to-limit-container-privilege-with-socket-activation/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-02T16:01:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using socket activation with the –network=none option limits an intruder’s ability to use a compromised container as a starting point for attacks on other devices. Read More at Enable Sysadmin
The post How to limit container privilege with socket activation appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erik Sjölund</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SQL Server Sample Bulk Data]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=202706</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/sql-server-sample-bulk-data/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-01T18:55:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is comma seperated value data useful for other tutorials such as: https://linuxhint.com/sql-server-bulk-insert/ id,firstname,lastname,email,Country,profession 100,Emilia,Vastah,Emilia.Vastah@mail.io,Saint Vincent and the Grenadines,developer 101,Edith,Masao,Edith.Masao@mail.io,Colombia,doctor 102,Kellen,Yusuk,Kellen.Yusuk@mail.io,Nicaragua,police officer 103,Amara,Roscoe,Amara.Roscoe@mail.io,Saint Vincent and the Grenadines,police officer 104,Consuela,Karylin,Consuela.Karylin@mail.io,Chad,doctor 105,Vevay,Ellord,Vevay.Ellord@mail.io,Afghanistan,worker 106,Valli,Ackerley,Valli.Ackerley@mail.io,Trinidad and Tobago,firefighter 107,Rubie,Jefferey,Rubie.Jefferey@mail.io,Monaco,developer 108,Netty,Gualtiero,Netty.Gualtiero@mail.io,Armenia,doctor 109,Adriana,Lunsford,Adriana.Lunsford@mail.io,Aruba,developer 110,Annora,Garek,Annora.Garek@mail.io,Indonesia,doctor 111,Viki,Thomasina,Viki.Thomasina@mail.io,Mali,doctor 112,Aeriela,Bivins,Aeriela.Bivins@mail.io,Canada,firefighter 113,Jennica,Mata,Jennica.Mata@mail.io,Madagascar,developer 114,Harmonia,Karna,Harmonia.Karna@mail.io,Norway,police officer 115,Nanete,Vivle,Nanete.Vivle@mail.io,Belarus,worker 116,Johna,Bates,Johna.Bates@mail.io,Liechtenstein,doctor 117,Therine,Lacombe,Therine.Lacombe@mail.io,Kazakhstan,doctor 118,Sharlene,Kathie,Sharlene.Kathie@mail.io,Ethiopia,worker 119,Marline,Calhoun,Marline.Calhoun@mail.io,Anguilla,doctor 120,Fayre,Reinke,Fayre.Reinke@mail.io,Samoa,firefighter 121,Kristina,Kaja,Kristina.Kaja@mail.io,Maldives,developer 122,Winny,Kaja,Winny.Kaja@mail.io,Holy See (Vatican City State),developer 123,Kathi,Sheng,Kathi.Sheng@mail.io,Belize,developer […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Admin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DNS settings to avoid email spoofing and phishing for unused domain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.cyberciti.biz/?p=1999</id>
        <link href="https://www.cyberciti.biz/security/dns-settings-to-avoid-email-spoofing-and-phishing-for-unused-domain/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-01T17:13:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you may know, email spoofing allows attackers to pose as someone else to gain illegal profit. For example, I only use webmaster@cyberciti.biz for communication, but someone might create a spoofed-up email, say info@opensourceflare.com, to trick someone. This is called email spoofing with fake headers as follow:
Date: Thu, 24 Oct 2021 12:46:10 
From: nixCraft <info@opensourceflare.com>
Reply-To: info@opensourceflare-email.com
To: <my@personal_gmail_com>
Correct headers are often not checked by receiving email servers, and my@personal_gmail_com may think the email is from me. Here is the thing I don't use opensourceflare.com for email communication at all. So how do I prevent illegitimate email traffic on my domain? In this tutorial, I will explain how to configure DNS settings that tell receiving email servers this domain is not configured for emailing purposes and the attacker maliciously sending email on my behalf.
Love this? sudo share_on: Twitter - Facebook - LinkedIn - Whatsapp - Reddit
The post DNS settings to avoid email spoofing and phishing for unused domain appeared first on nixCraft.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vivek Gite</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to manage pods in Podman with the REST API]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/how-to-manage-pods-in-podman-with-the-rest-api/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/how-to-manage-pods-in-podman-with-the-rest-api/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-01T16:01:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how to configure, inspect, and start pods in Podman with the REST API. Read More at Enable Sysadmin
The post How to manage pods in Podman with the REST API appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Guzik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Padloc: An Intuitive Open-Source Password Manager]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=100358</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/padloc/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-01T11:53:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An open-source password manager with a pleasing user interface, available cross-platform. Let's take a look!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ankush Das</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YAML Comments]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=192638</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/yaml-comments/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-01T03:44:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A guide on understanding the concept of the YAML comments and using the conventional method to add comments in a YAML file using the “#” character.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Reursora</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds Releases Linux 5.19 - From an Apple Silicon MacBook]]></title>
        <id>https://apple.slashdot.org/story/22/07/31/2326216/linus-torvalds-releases-linux-519---from-an-apple-silicon-macbook?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://apple.slashdot.org/story/22/07/31/2326216/linus-torvalds-releases-linux-519---from-an-apple-silicon-macbook?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-31T23:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Linus Torvalds just released Linux 5.19 as stable for the newest version of the Linux kernel..." reports Phoronix. 

But they also note that on the Linux kernel mailing list, "Torvalds went on to write about his Arm-based MacBook [running an AArch64 Apple M1 SoC]... now under Linux thanks to the work of the Asahi Linux project." 

Torvalds wrote:

[T]he most interesting part here is that I did the release (and am writing this) on an arm64 laptop. It's something I've been waiting for for a _loong_ time, and it's finally reality, thanks to the Asahi team. We've had arm64 hardware around running Linux for a long time, but none of it has really been usable as a development platform until now. 

It's the third time I'm using Apple hardware for Linux development — I did it many years ago for powerpc development on a ppc970 machine. And then a decade+ ago when the Macbook Air was the only real thin-and-lite around. And now as an arm64 platform. 

Not that I've used it for any real work, I literally have only been doing test builds and boots and now the actual release tagging. But I'm trying to make sure that the next time I travel, I can travel with this as a laptop and finally dogfooding the arm64 side too.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's New in Linux Mint 21 Cinnamon]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/31/1922217/whats-new-in-linux-mint-21-cinnamon?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/31/1922217/whats-new-in-linux-mint-21-cinnamon?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-31T19:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today saw the release of Linux Mint 21 "Vanessa" Cinnamon Edition, a long term support release (supported until 2027). 

Release notes at LinuxMint.com promise that it comes with "refinements and many new features to make your desktop experience more comfortable."

Among the highlights: its Bluetooth manager is now Blueman (instead of Blueberry).
Blueberry depended on gnome-bluetooth, which was developed exclusively for GNOME. In contrast, Blueman relies on the standard Bluez stack which works everywhere and can even be used or queried from the command line. The Blueman manager and tray icon provide many features that weren't available in Blueberry and a lot more information which can be used to monitor your connection or troubleshoot Bluetooth issues. 

Out of the box Blueman features bet…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use AWS IAM PassRole Permission]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=170317</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/aws-iam-passrole-permission/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-31T09:44:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practical guide on how to use the “IAM Passrole” permission in AWS to connect an EC2 instance with the S3 bucket following specific steps and policy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Reursora</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Are Linux NIS and NIS+]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=201364</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/linux-nis-nis-plus/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T22:26:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practical guide on how NIS and NIS+ work and the key differences and similarities between the two frameworks in considering when to use them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kennedy Brian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Story Behind Google's In-house Desktop Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/30/037202/the-story-behind-googles-in-house-desktop-linux?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/30/037202/the-story-behind-googles-in-house-desktop-linux?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T16:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["For more than a decade, Google has been baking and eating its own homemade Linux desktop distribution," writes Computerworld. 

Long-time Slashdot reader waspleg shared their report:

The first version was Goobuntu. (As you'd guess from the name, it was based on Ubuntu.) In 2018, Google moved its in-house Linux desktop from the Goobuntu to a new Linux distro, the Debian-based gLinux. Why? Because, as Google explained, Ubuntu's Long Term Support (LTS) two-year release "meant that we had to upgrade every machine in our fleet of over 100,000 devices before the end-of-life date of the OS." 

That was a pain. Add in the time-consuming need to fully customize engineers' PCs, and Google decided that it cost too much. Besides, the "effort to upgrade our Goobuntu fleet usually took the better part of a year. With a two-year support window, there was only one year left until we had to go through the same process all over again for the next LTS. This entire process was a huge stress factor for our team, as we got hundreds of bugs with requests for help for corner cases." 

So, when Google had enough of that, it moved to Debian Linux (though not just vanilla Debian). The company created a rolling Debian distribution: GLinux Rolling Debian Testing (Rodete). The idea is that users and developers are best served by giving them the latest updates and patches as they're created and deemed ready for production. 
Google's using what appears to be an automated build system (along with virtualized test suites, and eventually "incremental canarying"), the article points out. The end result? 

"The entire gLinux development team consists of a single on-duty release engineer position that rotates among team members."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Install Latest Vim 9.0 on Ubuntu Based Linux Distributions]]></title>
        <id>http://itsfoss.com/?p=12084</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/install-latest-vim-ubuntu/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T15:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This quick tutorial shows the steps for installing the latest version of Vim on Ubuntu-based Linux distributions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SpiralLinux: The New Distro Making Debian Easier for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99674</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/spirallinux-review/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T07:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SpiralLinux aims to provide a simplified and out-of-the-box Debian experience. Does it succeed in doing so? Read in this review.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sagar Sharma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Flush the DNS Cache on Ubuntu 22.04]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200221</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/flush-dns-cache-ubuntu-22-04/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:58:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step guide on how to manually flush the DNS cache on Ubuntu 22.04, what DNS is and its benefits, and why it’s essential to flush DNS cache.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Karim Buzdar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logical NOT in PyTorch]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=201148</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/logical-not-pytorch/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:51:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article explains the torch.logical_not() in PyTorch is performed on a single tensor object. It returns True if the value is False or 0 and vice versa.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gottumukkala Sravan Kumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Install Terminator on Ubuntu 22.04]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200264</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/install-terminator-ubuntu-22-04/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:50:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step guide on how to install Terminator on Ubuntu 22.04 by showing how to install and uninstall Terminator and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Karim Buzdar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to if the Object is a PyTorch Tensor and Return the Metadata of a Tensor in PyTorch?]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200223</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/object-pytorch-tensor-return-metadata-tensor-pytorch/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:50:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is possible to check whether the given object is a tensor or not. torch.is_tensor() is used to check whether the given object is tensor or not.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gottumukkala Sravan Kumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Install AnyDesk on Ubuntu 22.04]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200225</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/install-anydesk-ubuntu-22-04/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:50:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The AnyDesk is a smart application that is supported by almost all operating systems. This article explains all steps to install the AnyDesk in Ubuntu 22.04.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Karim Buzdar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Exit a Function in Python]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200208</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/exit-function-python/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:49:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step guide that shows how to exit a function in Python using explicit and implicit return statements so that the program can quit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Salotra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epoll 7 C Function]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200134</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/epoll-7-c-function/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:48:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guide on the use of epoll 7 C function to perform the socket programming and check the various file descriptors to determine if the input and output are viable.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Omar Farooq</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gawk Scripting Usage Examples]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200135</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/gawk-scripting-usage/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:48:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practical guide on how to use gawk scripting in Linux by using the different patterns to extract and manipulate the lines of data and the examples of its usage.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denis Kariuki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dlsym() 3 C Function]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200133</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/dlsym-3-c-function/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:48:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The dlsym() function goal is to find the address of a defined symbol specified in a DLL that has been made accessible via a dlopen() function call.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Omar Farooq</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Random Color]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200132</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/css-random-color/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:48:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A guide on using simple CSS Random Color techniques to randomly change the color of some HTML elements by the “pickColor” function to randomly pick one color.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aqsa Yasin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Order]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200131</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/css-order/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:48:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A guide that explains how to use “order” CSS property in the HTML code, containing an example that used “div” elements to portray “order” CSS property.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aqsa Yasin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS List Style Type]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200064</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/css-list-style-type/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:47:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tutorial on the CSS list style with their types, ordered and unordered lists, and implementing a few styles to see how these properties work using examples.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aqsa Yasin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Indent Second Line]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200063</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/css-indent-second-line/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:47:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step guide that shows how to indent a second line in CSS including two examples and an explanation of text indent property.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aqsa Yasin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Flex Order]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200062</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/css-flex-order/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:47:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A guide on using the CSS flex order property to create a flexbox and flex counters inside it. The order of the flex is applied by adding colors and text.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aqsa Yasin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Delay]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200065</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/css-delay/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:46:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step guide on how to utilize the CSS delay property in HTML including transition delay widthwise, height-wise, and animation delay.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aqsa Yasin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Counters]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200061</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/css-counters/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:46:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A guide on using CSS counters by maximizing several functions of the CSS counter property in the Hypertext Markup language to assign numbers to any element.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aqsa Yasin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create First Spring Boot Application]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200018</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/create-first-spring-boot-application/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practical guide on the steps to create a simple spring boot application and how to add more dependencies to create a more functional and web-based applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Irfan Khan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Counting Sort Complexity]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200017</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/counting-sort-time-complexity/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Comprehensive guide about the counting sort, its algorithm, operations, time complexity, the memory space and coding illustrated by sorting the integers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chrysanthus Forcha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compute the Logarithm of Elements of a Tensor in PyTorch]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200016</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/compute-logarithm-elements-tensor-pytorch/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:30:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article explains log() in PyTorch is used to return the natural logarithm of all the elements present in the tensor object. It takes only one parameter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gottumukkala Sravan Kumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Change the View of PyTorch Tensor]]></title>
        <id>https://linuxhint.com/?p=200015</id>
        <link href="https://linuxhint.com/change-view-pytorch-tensor/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T06:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article explains the view() in PyTorch is used to change the tensor object view by converting it into a specified number of rows and columns.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gottumukkala Sravan Kumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[People of Open Source: Neville Spiteri, Wevr]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/people-of-open-source-neville-spiteri-wevr/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/people-of-open-source-neville-spiteri-wevr/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-29T22:41:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neville Spiteri is the co-founder/CEO of Wevr and a member of the Academy Software Foundation. Learn more about Neville here.
The post People of Open Source: Neville Spiteri, Wevr appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Linux Foundation</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Sysadmin Appreciation Day: 2022’s top articles for sysadmins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/happy-sysadmin-appreciation-day-2022s-top-articles-for-sysadmins/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/happy-sysadmin-appreciation-day-2022s-top-articles-for-sysadmins/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-29T16:01:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thank you to all of the system administrators who keep our systems up and running, patched, and deployed every day of the year. Check out our most popular articles for sysadmins. Read More at Enable Sysadmin
The post Happy Sysadmin Appreciation Day: 2022’s top articles for sysadmins appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Carrigan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the OpenGEH (Green Energy Hub) Project]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/what-is-the-opengeh-green-energy-hub-project/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/what-is-the-opengeh-green-energy-hub-project/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-29T05:36:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenGEH ( GEH stands for Green Energy Hub ) enables fast, flexible settlement and hourly measurements of production and consumption of electricity.
The post What is the OpenGEH (Green Energy Hub) Project appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Linux Foundation</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[7 Docks to Customize Your Linux Desktop]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99401</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/best-linux-docks/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-29T04:46:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Docks are one of the several ways you can customize your desktop. Here are some of the best docks that will help you change the default look of your desktop Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sagar Sharma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 things sysadmins should know about software development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/5-things-sysadmins-should-know-about-software-development/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/5-things-sysadmins-should-know-about-software-development/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-28T16:01:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advances in edge computing, machine learning, and intelligent applications make sysadmins more important than ever in the software development process. Read More at Enable Sysadmin
The post 5 things sysadmins should know about software development appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicole Lama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice vs OpenOffice: All You Need to Know?]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=100117</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/libreoffice-vs-openoffice/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-28T04:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A comparison of the two of the most popular open source office software that are also similar in many respects. This article explains the similarities and differences between LibreOffice and OpenOffice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ankush Das</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CRob on Software Security Education and SIRTs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/crob-on-software-security-education-and-sirts/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/crob-on-software-security-education-and-sirts/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-28T02:58:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CRob, with Intel and the OpenSSF, talks about open source software security education and training with Alan Shimel of TechStrong TV.
The post CRob on Software Security Education and SIRTs appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Whiting</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux tool alternatives: 6 replacements for traditional favorites]]></title>
        <id>https://www.linux.com/news/linux-tool-alternatives-6-replacements-for-traditional-favorites/</id>
        <link href="https://www.linux.com/news/linux-tool-alternatives-6-replacements-for-traditional-favorites/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-27T16:01:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Consider swapping Linux tools for these alternatives that provide more features and functionality. Read More at Enable Sysadmin
The post Linux tool alternatives: 6 replacements for traditional favorites appeared first on Linux.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jose Vicente Nunez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[6 Tips and Tools to Enhance Your Flatpak Experience in Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=100144</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/flatpak-tips-tweaks/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-27T07:42:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you love using Flatpak applications, here are a few tips, tools, and tweaks to make your Flatpak experience better and smoother.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Sours On Creative Commons 'No Rights Reserved' License]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/26/2028205/fedora-sours-on-creative-commons-no-rights-reserved-license?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/26/2028205/fedora-sours-on-creative-commons-no-rights-reserved-license?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-26T20:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[waspleg writes: Fedora, the popular Linux distribution, will no longer incorporate software licensed under CC0, the Creative Commons "No Rights Reserved" license. In order to support the wide re-use of copyrighted content in new works, CC0 provides authors "a way to waive all their copyright and related rights in their works to the fullest extent allowed by law." The license arose in response to the 1998 Sonny Bono Copyright Term Extension Act (CTEA), which extended the duration of copyright by 20 years at the expense of the public domain. But CC0 explicitly says the licensor does not waive patent rights, which for free and open source software (FOSS) is a potential problem. That means, for instance as described here, if you use CC0-licensed code in your project, and the author of that code later claims your project is infringing a patent they own regarding that code, your defense will be limited. Avoiding the use of CC0-licensed code is one way to steer clear of these so-called submarine patents that could years later torpedo you. 

In a message to The Fedora Project's mailing list for legal issues, Richard Fontana, a technology lawyer for Red Hat (which sponsors Fedora), explained that while CC0 is cited as a "good license," it won't be for much longer. "We plan to classify CC0 as allowed-content only, so that CC0 would no longer be allowed for code," said Fontana. "This is a fairly unusual change and may have an impact on a nontrivial number of Fedora packages (that is not clear to me right now), and we may grant a carveout for existing packages that include CC0-covered code." Fontana said there's a growing consensus in the FOSS community that licenses without any form of patent licensing or forbearance aren't suitable. CC0, he said, like other Creative Commons licenses, includes a clause that explicitly states no patent rights are waived by the licensor.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Koodo is an All-in-one Open Source eBook Reader App for Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=100105</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/koodo-ebook-reader/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-25T08:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Koodo is an open source, cross-platform eBook reader application with tons of features to improve your reading experience.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Install Pamac GUI Package Manager in Arch Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=98953</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/install-pamac-arch-linux/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-24T11:37:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pamac is an awesome GUI-based package manager from the developers of Manjaro Linux. Here's how you can get Pamac in Arch Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anuj Sharma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[T2 SDE Linux 22.6 Released - and an AI Bot Contributed More Revisions Than Humans]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/23/0514203/t2-sde-linux-226-released---and-an-ai-bot-contributed-more-revisions-than-humans?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/23/0514203/t2-sde-linux-226-released---and-an-ai-bot-contributed-more-revisions-than-humans?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-23T17:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["T2 SDE is not just a regular Linux distribution," reads the announcement. "It is a flexible Open Source System Development Environment or Distribution Build Kit (others might even name it Meta Distribution). T2 allows the creation of custom distributions with state of the art technology, up-to-date packages and integrated support for cross compilation." 


Slashdot reader ReneR writes: The T2 project released a major milestone update, shipping full support for 25 CPU architectures, variants, and C libraries. Support for cross compiling was further improved to also cover Rust, Ada, ObjC, Fortran, and Go! 

This is also the first major release where an AI powered package update bot named 'data' contributed more changes than human contributors combined! [Data: 164, humans: 141] 

T2 is known for its sophisticated cross compile support as well as supporting nearly all existing CPU architectures: alpha, arc, arm, arm64, avr32, hppa, ia64, m68k, mipsel, mips64, nios2, ppc, ppc64-32, ppc64le, riscv, riscv64, s390x, spare, sparc64, superh x86, x86-64 and x32 for a wide use in Embedded systems. The project also still supports the Sony PS3, Sgi Octane and Sun workstations as well as state of the art ARM64, RISCV64 as well as AMD64 for regular cloud, server, or simply enthusiast workstation use.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat's Next Steps, According to Its New CEO]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/23/0121228/red-hats-next-steps-according-to-its-new-ceo?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/23/0121228/red-hats-next-steps-according-to-its-new-ceo?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-23T14:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IBM saw its hybrid-cloud revenue jump 18% to $5.9 billion in the last three months, reports ZDNet — while also experiencing "its highest sales growth in a decade. 

"Much of that is due to its stand-alone Red Hat division."

True, Red Hat sales increased by "only" 12%, which is low by Red Hat standards but darn good by any other standard. So what will Red Hat do now that it has a new CEO, Matt Hicks, and chairman, Paul Cormier? 

The answer: Stay the course. 

In an interview, Hicks, who's been with Red Hat since 2006, said, "[We'll keep using] the same core fundamentals that we built 20-plus years ago." Why? Because the combination of Linux, open-source software, and top support, "continues to play in new markets, whether that's the shift to cloud and cloud services or to edge computing. In the next couple of quarters. we'll just focus on executing. There's great momentum right now around the open hybrid cloud." 


It's not just the cloud, though. Hicks continued, "We have a lot of opportunities. We're also working with General Motors on Ultifi, GM's end-to-end software platform, and two days ago, we announced a partnership with ABB, one of the world's leading manufacturing automation companies. It's pretty cool to see Linux and open source technologies being pulled into these totally new markets in the industry. So my job is not to change anything but keep us executing and capturing the opportunities ahead...." 

Moving to the technical side, I asked about Red Hat and CentOS. Hicks replied, "I think it was a necessary shift and change. I'm a big believer in what makes open source work is the contribution cycle, and that wasn't happening with CentOS." 

Cormier adds that going forward Linux's biggest contribution to the world may be innovation (and not accessbility), "and that needs contributions. Without it driving open source and Linux, the cloud wouldn't be here."







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top 10 Best Music Players for Linux in 2022]]></title>
        <id>http://itsfoss.com/?p=15389</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/best-music-players-linux/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-23T04:36:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It isn't rocket science to play music on Linux, but you should have a great experience with a good music player!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ankush Das</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing the “Pending Update of Firefox snap” Error in Ubuntu]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=100032</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/pending-update-firefox-ubuntu/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-22T03:15:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping on seeing a persistent "pending update of Firefox snap" message that doesn't go away even if you restart the browser or the Ubuntu system? Here's what you should do.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dell XPS Developer Edition Will Soon Arrive With Ubuntu Linux 22.04]]></title>
        <id>https://news.slashdot.org/story/22/07/21/229214/the-dell-xps-developer-edition-will-soon-arrive-with-ubuntu-linux-2204?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/22/07/21/229214/the-dell-xps-developer-edition-will-soon-arrive-with-ubuntu-linux-2204?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-22T00:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Dell XPS 13 Plus Developer Edition with Ubuntu 22.04 Long Term Support (LTS) will arrive on August 23rd. "This means, of course, Canonical and Dell officially have been certified for Ubuntu 22.04 LTS," writes ZDNet's Steven Vaughan-Nichols. "So if you already have a current XPS 13 Plus, you can install Ubuntu 22.04 and automatically receive the same hardware-optimized experience that will ship with the new Developer Edition." From the report: What this certification means is that all of XPS's components have been tested to deliver the best possible experience out of the box. Ubuntu-certified devices are based on Long Term Support (LTS) releases and therefore receive updates for up to 10 years. So if you actually still have an XPS 13 that came with Ubuntu back in the day, it's still supported today. [...] Dell and Canonical have been at this for years. Today's Dell's Developer Editions are the official continuation of Project Sputnik. This initiative began 10 years ago to create high-end Dell systems with Ubuntu preinstalled. These were, and are, designed with programmer input and built for developers.
 
As Jaewook Woo, Dell's product manager, Linux, explained: "XPS is an innovation portal for Dell -- from its application of cutting-edge technology to experimentation of new user interfaces and experiential design. By bringing the enhanced performance and power management features of Ubuntu 22.04 LTS to our most advanced premium laptop, Dell and Canonical reinforce our joint commitment to continue delivering the best computing experience for developers using Ubuntu."
 
The forthcoming Dell XPS Plus Developer Edition's specifications are impressive. The base configuration is powered by a 12th-generation Intel i5 1240P processor that runs up to 4.4GHz. For graphics, it uses Intel Iris Xe Graphics. This backs up the 13.4-inch 1920x1200 60Hz display. For storage, it uses a 512GB SSD. The list price is $1,389.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update a Single Package With apt Command in Ubuntu and Debian]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99346</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/apt-upgrade-single-package/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-20T05:32:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The apt command usually upgrades the entire upgradable packages at once. Here's how to upgrade only a single package or a selected few packages in Ubuntu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Distro For Apple Silicon Macs Is Already Up and Running On the Brand-New M2]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/19/0012221/linux-distro-for-apple-silicon-macs-is-already-up-and-running-on-the-brand-new-m2?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/19/0012221/linux-distro-for-apple-silicon-macs-is-already-up-and-running-on-the-brand-new-m2?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-19T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An anonymous reader quotes a report from Ars Technica: Unlike Intel Macs, Apple silicon Macs were designed to run only Apple's software. But the developers on the Asahi Linux team have been working to change that, painstakingly reverse-engineering support for Apple's processors and other Mac hardware and releasing it as a work-in-progress distro that can actually boot up and run on bare metal, no virtualization required. The Asahi Linux team put out a new release today with plenty of additions and improvements. Most notably, the distro now supports the M1 Ultra and the Mac Studio and has added preliminary support for the M2 MacBook Pro (which has been tested firsthand by the team) and the M2 MacBook Air (which hasn't been tested but ought to work). Preliminary Bluetooth support for all Apple silicon Macs has also been added, though the team notes that it works poorly when connected to a 2.4GHz Wi-Fi network because "Wi-Fi/Bluetooth coexistence isn't properly configured yet."
 
There are still many other things that aren't working properly, including the USB-A ports on the Studio, faster-than-USB-2.0 speeds from any Type-C/Thunderbolt ports, and GPU acceleration, but progress is being made on all of those fronts. GPU work in particular is coming along, with a "prototype driver" that is "good enough to run real graphics applications and benchmarks" already up and running, though it's not included in this release. The Asahi team has said in the past that it expects support for new chips to be relatively easy to add to Asahi since Apple's chip designers frequently reuse things and don't make extensive hardware changes unless there's a good reason for it. Adding basic support for the M2 to Asahi happened over the course of a single 12-hour development session, and just "a few days" of additional effort were needed to get the rest of the hardware working as well as it does with M1-based Macs.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Uninstall Deb Packages in Ubuntu]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99678</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/uninstall-deb-ubuntu/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-19T11:41:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Installing deb files is quite simple. Removing deb files might not be that simple but it's not too complicated either. Here's all you need to know about deleting deb packages from Ubuntu Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Install Discord on Manjaro and Other Arch Linux Derivatives]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99022</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/install-discord-arch-manjaro/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-19T05:29:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discord is a popular service among open source communities. Learn to install the desktop client of Discord on Manjaro and other Arch-based Linux distros.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anuj Sharma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AppFlowy: An Open-Source Alternative to Notion]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99609</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/appflowy/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-18T10:39:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AppFlowy aims to be an open-source replacement to Notion, providing you with better privacy. Let us explore more about it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sagar Sharma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can a Fork Save Cutefish OS (or Its Desktop)?]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/17/0143210/can-a-fork-save-cutefish-os-or-its-desktop?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/17/0143210/can-a-fork-save-cutefish-os-or-its-desktop?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-17T15:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April ZDNet called its beta "the cutest Linux distro you'll ever use," praising the polished "incredible elegance" of Debian-based Cutefish OS, with its uncluttered, MacOS-like "Cutefish DE" desktop. 

But now CutefishOS.com times out, with at least one Reddit user complaining "their email is not responding" and seeking contributors for a fork. 

But meanwhile, the technology site DebugPoint.com shares another update:
It looks like the OpenMandriva project is already continuing with the development of the Cutefish DE (not the OS) for its own OS. For more details, visit the Matrix discussion page. 

Besides, it's worth mentioning that Arch Linux already have the Cutefish desktop packages in the community repo. You can even install it as a standalone desktop environment in Arch Linux with easy steps. As you can see, it is easier to maintain the desktop environment to continue its development because the structure is already out there. 

I have tested and reviewed hundreds of distros for years, and Cutefish OS is the promising one with its stunning desktop environment. It was written from the ground up with QML and C++ and took advantage of KWin. It would have been an attractive desktop as a separate component and could have been another great option besides KDE Plasma or GNOME. 

Many open-source projects are born and die every year, and it's unfortunate to see the situation of Cutefish OS. I hope an official fork comes up soon, and we all can contribute to it.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[13 Ways to Tweak Nautilus File Manager in Linux to Get More Out of it]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99575</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/nautilus-tips-tweaks/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-16T05:54:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nautilus, aka GNOME Files, is a good file manager with plenty of features. You can further enhance your experience by using these extensions, tweaks and tips.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Ultimate Guide to Epic Games Store on Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99483</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/epic-games-linux/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-15T05:51:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Though it is not officially available, it's not that complicated to use Epic Games Store on Linux. Here are various ways you can play Epic games in Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ankush Das</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing “Command ‘python’ not found” Error in Ubuntu Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=98306</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/python-not-found-ubuntu/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-14T06:13:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tried running python command but Ubuntu complains that python command is not found? It may already be installed but you'll still see the error. Here's why!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[9 Rather Unknown Ways of Using Neofetch in Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99461</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/using-neofetch/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-13T10:46:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neofetch displays the system information and distribution logo in the terminal. It can be tweaked to change the looks and feel of its output in surprising new ways.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Names New CEO]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/13/0545252/red-hat-names-new-ceo?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/13/0545252/red-hat-names-new-ceo?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat announced that Paul Cormier, the company's CEO and president since 2020, is stepping over to become chairman of the board. Matt Hicks, a Red Hat veteran and the company's head of products and technologies, will replace Cormier as president and CEO. ZDNet reports: It had been rumored at May 2022's Red Hat Summit that Cormier, who had been with Red Hat for over 14 years, might retire soon. That rumor wasn't true, but he is moving to a "somewhat" less demanding position. That said, as Stephanie Wonderlick, Red Hat's VP of Brand Experience + Communication, said, "I don't think Red Hat would have become Red Hat without Paul Cormier." [...]
 
As for Hicks, he's a popular figure in the company. He's known as a hands-on leader. Hicks joined Red Hat in 2006 as a developer working on porting…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[List Upgradable Packages With apt Command in Ubuntu]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99342</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/apt-list-upgradable/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-12T05:05:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You don't always have to upgrade all the packages at once. With apt command, you can list the upgradable packages first and then decide which ones to upgrade.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to protect Linux against rogue USB devices using USBGuard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.cyberciti.biz/?p=1985</id>
        <link href="https://www.cyberciti.biz/security/how-to-protect-linux-against-rogue-usb-devices-using-usbguard/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-11T15:56:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[usbgurd
You deployed a perfect firewall and other network security policies preventing unauthorized access to the user's desktop computer over a network. However, you still need to block USB device access. We can configure a Linux desktop security policy to protect your computer against rogue USB devices (a.k.a. BadUSB) by implementing essential allow and blocklisting capabilities based on device attributes. For instance, I can deﬁne what kind of USB devices are authorized and how a USB device interacts with the Linux system. For example, I can define policy allowing Yubikey with serial number "XYZ" and USB LTE modem with serial # "ABC." Every other USB device access is denied by default.
Love this? sudo share_on: Twitter - Facebook - LinkedIn - Whatsapp - Reddit
The post How to protect Linux against rogue USB devices using USBGuard appeared first on nixCraft.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vivek Gite</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tropy: An Open-Source App to Organize Your Research Photos]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99405</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/tropy/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-11T14:14:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An app to help you explore research photos, and documents without losing out on important contextual information about them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ankush Das</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Six Ground-Breaking New Linux Laptops Released in the Last Two Weeks]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/10/2019230/six-ground-breaking-new-linux-laptops-released-in-the-last-two-weeks?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/10/2019230/six-ground-breaking-new-linux-laptops-released-in-the-last-two-weeks?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-10T20:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the last two weeks, six new Linux laptops have hit the market (or were announced). "The Linux hardware scene is getting better by the day," writes the site FOSS Weekly:


Star Labs teases its new StarFighter Linux Laptop with a 4K (10-bit IPS) display. MNT Research introduces a "more affordable" 7-inch mini Linux laptop, the MNT Pocket Reform.
 KDE's Slimbook 4 is here with AMD Ryzen 7 5700U processor and a better battery, starting from $1,000. "Buying from Slimbook supports KDE development too," notes Gaming on Linux, adding that there's a choice of 14 or 15.6 inch displays. TUXEDO's Pulse 15 — Gen2 (also with an AMD Ryzen 7 5700U processor) has a 15-inch HiDPI WQHD 165Hz display, along with eight cores and 16 threads. (And the Register notes its twin cooling fans, "allowing them to overclock the chip and run it at 35W," and a choice of distros.)
Pre-orders have opened for the Roma — the first RISC-V Laptop (which may ship in September). Ars Technica reports they're offering "free Silicon upgrades" — that is free system-on-a-chip and system-on-module upgrades for its quad-core RISC-V CPU. And there's also a companion NPU/GPU, notes a blog post at RISCV.org, "for the fastest, seamless RISC-V native software development available." (As well as "early access to next-generation laptop and accessory upgrades at generous discounts or for free.") The blog post calls it a "Web3-friendly platform with NFT creation and publication plus integrated MetaMask-style wallet." System 76's "Lemur" Alder Lake- and coreboot-powered laptop arrives with 14 hours of battery life.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>EditorDavid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Microsoft Office on Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99173</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/use-microsoft-office-linux/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-09T07:20:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In dire need of using Microsoft Office on your Linux desktop? Here are your options for getting MS Office on Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sagar Sharma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alder Lake-Powered Linux Laptop Arrives With 14 Hours of Battery Life]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/07/2243250/alder-lake-powered-linux-laptop-arrives-with-14-hours-of-battery-life?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/07/2243250/alder-lake-powered-linux-laptop-arrives-with-14-hours-of-battery-life?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[System76, the Colorado-based Linux laptop, desktop, and server specialist, has announced a new highly portable laptop with an Intel Alder Lake processor inside. Tom's Hardware reports: The new Lemur Pro(opens in new tab) is a "lighter than Air" 14-inch form factor laptop with excellent battery life and attractions such as open firmware (powered by Coreboot) and a 180-degree hinge. In addition, buyers can choose to go with Pop!_OS 22.04 LTS or Ubuntu 22.04 LTS pre-installed. The new Lemur Pro has many attractive modern features you might see advertised in many rival mainstream thin and light designs. However, the special sauce here is the "System76 Open Firmware with Coreboot." Coreboot, known initially as LinuxBIOS, is significant as it is an open-source BIOS implementation embraced by Linux users. It is lightweight, flexible, and feature-rich. [...]
 
System76 has designed the Lemur Pro with monitor-based docking in mind. It envisions users connecting to a big screen using the USB-C connection to benefit from the more expansive workspace and laptop charging. Like Windows, Linux had to have some serious tinkering under the hood to prepare for the mix of Performance and Efficiency cores in Alder Lake chips. However, rest assured, efficient hybrid scheduling is taken care of with the two OS options that can be pre-installed on the Lemur Pro.
 
System76 allows customers to configure and buy Lemur Pro laptops right now. There are many RAM and storage configurations to pick through, and you can add external keyboards and monitors to the bundle. The entry price with an Intel Core i5-1235U, 8GB RAM, 240GB of storage, and no extras is $1,149. However, the Core i7-1255U model is a bit of a stretch, adding $200 to the base price for the faster CPU clocks.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Umbrel: Unique Linux Distro for Self Hosting Open Source Software for Your Homelab]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=98941</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/umbrel-review/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-08T04:05:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to set up a homelab but not comfortable with all the complexity? Umbrel enables you to self host multiple open source software easily.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pratham Patel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Systemd Creator Lands At Microsoft]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/06/2348255/systemd-creator-lands-at-microsoft?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/06/2348255/systemd-creator-lands-at-microsoft?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-07T01:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, Phoronix reported that the lead developer of systemd, Lennart Poettering, left Red Hat. "It turns out he had joined Microsoft and [is] continuing his work on systemd," writes Phoronix's Michael Larabel in a new report. He continues: While some may not always align with his views or approaches to handling some things, there is no overstating his enormous contributions to the Linux/open-source world and his dedication to advancing the ecosystem over the years. This may take many by surprise but let's not forget Microsoft has over time employed a number of Linux developers and other prominent open-source developers... Microsoft currently employs Python creator Guido van Rossum, GNOME creator Miguel de Icaza had been employed by Microsoft from 2016 when they acquired Xamarin to earlier this year when he left, Nat Friedman as part of Xamarin-Microsoft served as GitHub CEO following Microsoft's acquisition, Gentoo Linux founder Daniel Robbins was previously employed by Microsoft, Steve French as the Linux CIFS/SMB2/SMB3 maintainer and Samba team member works for Microsoft, and Microsoft employs/previously-employed a large number of upstream Linux developers like Matteo Croce, Matthew Wilcox, Shyam Prasad N, Michael Kelley, and many others beyond just the usual immediately recognizable names to Linux enthusiasts/developers. It was also just earlier this year that Christian Brauner as another longtime Linux kernel developer joined Microsoft. Christian Brauner is Berlin-based like Lennart and moved on to Microsoft after the past half-decade at Canonical working on the Linux kernel, LXC, systemd, and more.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's xCloud Game Streaming Looks Worse On Linux Than Windows]]></title>
        <id>https://games.slashdot.org/story/22/07/06/2040206/microsofts-xcloud-game-streaming-looks-worse-on-linux-than-windows?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://games.slashdot.org/story/22/07/06/2040206/microsofts-xcloud-game-streaming-looks-worse-on-linux-than-windows?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-07T00:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As noted by a Reddit user and confirmed by Ars Technica, Microsoft's xCloud game streaming looks noticeable worse when running on Linux than Windows. From the report: With the Linux User-Agent, edges are generally less sharp and colors are a little more washed out. The difference is even more apparent if you zoom in on the Forza logo and menu text, which shows a significant reduction in clarity. Interestingly, the dip in quality seems to go away if you enable "Clarity Boost, an Edge-exclusive feature that "provid[es] the optimal look and feel while playing Xbox games from the cloud," according to Microsoft. That's great for Linux users who switched over to Microsoft Edge when it launched on Linux last November. But Linux users who stick with Firefox, Chrome, or other browsers are currently…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 Tools to Generate and Have Fun With ASCII Art in Linux Terminal]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99287</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/ascii-art-linux-terminal/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-06T09:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Think Linux terminal is all about serious work? Think again. Here are a few fun things you can do with ASCII art in the terminal.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PulseAudio and Systemd Creator, Lennart Poettering, Reportedly Leaves Red Hat]]></title>
        <id>https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/05/2040215/pulseaudio-and-systemd-creator-lennart-poettering-reportedly-leaves-red-hat?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</id>
        <link href="https://linux.slashdot.org/story/22/07/05/2040215/pulseaudio-and-systemd-creator-lennart-poettering-reportedly-leaves-red-hat?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T22:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To much surprise, the lead developer of systemd Lennart Poettering who also led the creation of PulseAudio, Avahi, and has been a prolific free software contributor has reportedly left Red Hat. Michael Larabel writes via Phoronix: So far no public announcement appears to have been made, but according to a source has been reportedly removed from Red Hat's internal employee database. Yesterday Lennart did comment on the public Fedora devel mailing list to having now created a personal Red Hat Bugzilla account for his Fedora contributions after it was raised in bug reports and brought up on the mailing list that Lennart's Red Hat account is disabled. Emailing his Red Hat address this morning indeed yields an auto-response that it's no longer in use.
 
He's still active in systemd world with new commits made as of today, so it will be interesting to see where he ends up or his next moves with his vast Linux ecosystem expertise and pivotal role in spearheading systemd's direction.







Read more of this story at Slashdot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[12 New Features in Linux Mint 21]]></title>
        <id>https://itsfoss.com/?p=99198</id>
        <link href="https://itsfoss.com/linux-mint-21-features/"/>
        <updated>2022-07-04T15:31:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Development for Linux Mint 21 is going in full swing. Here is a sneak peek into the features of this much awaited distribution release.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>